Finding aid to the James Parker records, 1924-2005 Archives.Parker.1
The Metropolitan Museum of Art Archives
- Series I. Research, 1912-1997, n.d.; 31.0 Linear feet (72 boxes, 839 folders)
  - Subseries I.A. Card File, 1922-1933, 1943-1950, 1957-1996, n.d.; 25.0 Linear feet (60 boxes, 722 folders)
    - Furniture. U.S.A. (Box 31, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Chairs. Contains correspondence from John B. Hermanson, Boston University (1986) and to A.W. Duy, Jr. from Preston Remington, M.M.A. (1927). Contains 3 photographs.
    - Furniture. Welsh. (Box 31, Folder 2)
    - Gardens. (Box 31, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Dutch. English. French (treillages, containers for plants). German. Irish. Italian. U.S.A.
    - Glass and crystal. A - D. (Box 31, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Belgian. Bohemian. Chinese. Dutch. Contains memorandum to James J. Rorimer, M.M.A. re: Interim Report on the Pillet-Will and Paar Rooms (1964).
    - Glass and crystal. English. (Box 31, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Domes or vitrines. Glasses and bottles. Lighting. Waterford glass. Mirrors (16th - 17th centuries, 18th century, 19th - 20th centuries, labeled, verre églomisé). Contains correspondence from Eileen Harris (1991).See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Woodwork and interiors. English [5 of 5] for windows.See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Furniture. English. Regency [3 of 3] for convex mirrors.
    - Glass and crystal. Eyeglasses. (Box 31, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes French.
    - Glass and crystal. French (1 of 3). (Box 31, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Bottles and glasses. Crystal. Furniture. Domes or vitrines.See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Woodwork and interiors. French [11 of 11] for windows.
    - Glass and crystal. French (2 of 3). (Box 31, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Mirrors (Louis XIV, Régence, Louis XV, Louis XVI, late 18th century, Empire, Louis-Philippe, late 19th century, Makers, Art Nouveau [Lalique], 20th century).
    - Glass and crystal. French (3 of 3). (Box 31, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Paperweights. Verre églomisé. Verre églomisé mirrors. Verre églomisé furniture. Painted mirror glass.See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Glass and crystal. German.
    - Glass and crystal. German. (Box 31, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Furniture.
    - Glass and crystal. I. (Box 32, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Indonesian. Irish. Italian (furniture, crystal, lighting, mirrors - 16th - 17th centuries, 18th century, 19th century, 20th century).
    - Glass and crystal. P - U. (Box 32, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Portuguese. Russian. Spanish. Swedish. U.S.A.
    - Hardware. (Box 32, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Austrian. English. French. German. Italian. Includes small section on Horn.
    - Horology. A- B. (Box 32, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Belgian. Contains correspondence to John T. Sargent, Doubleday and Company Inc. (1980).See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.B. General / f. Clocks.
    - Horology. C - D. (Box 32, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Chinese. Danish. Dutch (barometers).
    - Horology. English. (Box 32, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes 19th century. [Mixed]. Contains correspondence from Arthur S. Vernay, Inc. (1928). Contains 1 photograph.
    - Horology. English. Barometers. (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Horology. English. Makers (A - S). (Box 32, Folder 8)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Peter D. Jones, c/o The Knickerbocker Club to Ashton Hawkins, M.M.A. (1969). Contains 1 photograph.
    - Horology. English. Makers (T - W). (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Horology. French. (Box 32, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Pre-Louis XIV. Louis XIV. Régence. Louis XV. Louis XVI. Empire. Provincial.See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.A. Card File / f. Furniture. French. Louis XV. Makers for Boulle.
    - Horology. French. Barometers. (Box 33, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Louis XIV. Régence. Louis XV. Louis XVI. Empire. Restoration. Makers. Cites - Bourbon, Chevallier, Passemant, Radiguet.
    - Horology. French. Makers (A - B). (Box 33, Folder 2)
      Note: Cites - Baillon, Bailly, Berthoud, Bertrand, Bouchet, Bourdier, Breguet, Brille.
    - Horology. French. Makers (C - D). (Box 33, Folder 3)
      Note: Cites - Causard, Champion, Chauvot, Chevallier, Collier, Cronier, Dubois, Dubuisson, Duchesne, du Tertre.
    - Horology. French. Makers (E - G). (Box 33, Folder 4)
      Note: Cites - Fieffé, Furet, Gallois, Gaudron, Gérard, Gille Laîné à Paris, Godon, Goyer, Gribelin, Gudin, Guydamour à Paris.
    - Horology. French. Makers (H - L). (Box 33, Folder 5)
      Note: Cites - Hémon, Hervé, Hilgers, Janvier, Kinable, Laurent, Lebon, Le Facheur, Le Loutre, Lenoir, Lepaute, Lépine, Le Roy, Le Sueur, Lieutaud.
    - Horology. French. Makers (M - Q). (Box 33, Folder 6)
      Note: Cites - Manière, Marguerite, Martin, Martinot, Masson, Mesnil, Moillot, Moinet, Moisy, Montjoie, Ninderviller, Panier, Passemant, Platier, Pochon.
    - Horology. French. Makers (R). (Box 33, Folder 7)
      Note: Cites - Rabby, Raingo, Renoir, Ridel, Robert, Robin, Roque. Contains correspondence from Anthony G. Victoria, Frederick P. Victoria and Son, Inc. (1983).
    - Horology. French. Makers (S - Z). (Box 33, Folder 8)
      Note: Cites - Schmit, Sotiau, Stollenerck, Thiout, Thonissen, Thuret, Voisin.
    - Horology. French. Makers (Mixed). (Box 33, Folder 9)
      Note: Contains materials that pertain to maker collaborations, as well as information on the relationships between and the education of various makers. Contains 1 photograph.
    - Horology. German. (Box 34, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes 19th century. Makers. Contains correspondence from Olivier Kraemer, Kraemer et Cie to Olga Raggio, M.M.A. (1989).
    - Horology. I. (Box 34, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Indian. Irish. Italian (makers, barometers).
    - Horology. J - U. (Box 34, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Japanese. Portuguese. Russian. Scottish. Spanish. Swedish. Swiss. U.S.A. Contains correspondence from Anita Reynolds (n.d.).
    - Indices. (Box 34, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes English. French. U.S.A. Larousse. Contains memorandum from William B. Walker, M.M.A. (1983).
    - Inkstands. (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Ironwork and other metals. A - E. (Box 34, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Belgian. Dutch. English. Contains correspondence from John S. Sudela (1977).
    - Ironwork and other metals. French (1 of 2). (Box 34, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes 18th - 19th centuries.
    - Ironwork and other metals. French (2 of 2). (Box 34, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes 20th century. Steel beds and other furniture.'Trick' dining room tables. Elevators.
    - Ironwork and other metals. G - U. (Box 34, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes German. Irish. Italian. Russian (Tula). Scottish. Spanish. Swiss. U.S.A. Contains correspondence from Katrina V.H. Taylor, Hillwood Museum (1991).
    - Ivories. A- D. (Box 34, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes 19th century. Austrian and German. Chinese. Dutch.See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.B. General / f. Ivories.
    - Ivories. E - G. (Box 35, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes English. Flemish. French. German. Contains 1 slide.
    - Ivories. I - R. (Box 35, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Indian. Italian. Portuguese. Russian. [Mixed].
    - Jewelry. (Box 35, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Austrian and Hungarian. Dutch and Belgian. English. French. German. Italian. Portuguese. Russian. Spanish. Swedish and Norwegian.
    - Lead. (Box 35, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes English. French.
    - Leathers. (Box 35, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Belgian. Dutch. English. French. German. Italian. Spanish.
    - Lighting. A - D. (Box 35, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Belgian. Czechoslovakian. Danish. Dutch (chandeliers). Contains memorandum from Mrs. Dalton, M.M.A. (1964) and an invoice from Beck Candle Corp. (1967).
    - Lighting. English (1 of 3). (Box 35, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes 17th century. Brass chandeliers. 18th century. Early Georgian.
    - Lighting. English (2 of 3). (Box 35, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Chippendale. Adam.
    - Lighting. English (3 of 3). (Box 35, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Croome Court. Regency. Victorian. Contains 1 photograph.
    - Lighting. French. Louis XIV (1 of 3). (Box 35, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Candelabras and candlesticks. Candle stands.
    - Lighting. French. Louis XIV (2 of 3). (Box 36, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Chandeliers.
    - Lighting. French. Louis XIV (3 of 3). (Box 36, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Lanterns. Wall brackets.
    - Lighting. French. Régence. (Box 36, Folder 3)
      Note: Contains correspondence with Bernard Kusinitz, Touro Synagogue (1989). Contains correspondence from Marcel Bissey (1963).
    - Lighting. French. Louis XV (1 of 3). (Box 36, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Candelabras and candlesticks. Porcelain candelabras and candlesticks. Candle stands.
    - Lighting. French. Louis XV (2 of 3). (Box 36, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Chandeliers. Porcelain chandeliers. Lanterns. Contains 2 slides.
    - Lighting. French. Louis XV (3 of 3). (Box 36, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Wall brackets. Porcelain wall brackets.
    - Lighting. French. Louis XVI (1 of 5). (Box 36, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Candelabras and candlesticks.
    - Lighting. French. Louis XVI (2 of 5). (Box 36, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Candelabras and candlesticks. Contains correspondence from Henry Sorensen (1975).
    - Lighting. French. Louis XVI (3 of 5). (Box 36, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Candle stands. Chandeliers. Lanterns. Hunting horns.
    - Lighting. French. Louis XVI (4 of 5). (Box 36, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Wall brackets.
    - Lighting. French. Louis XVI (5 of 5). (Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Lighting. French. Empire (1 of 2). (Box 37, Folder 2)
    - Lighting. French. Empire (2 of 2). (Box 37, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Chandeliers. Lamps. Lanterns. Wall brackets. Contains postcard from Janet Bryne (1965).
    - Lighting. French. Restoration. (Box 37, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Candelabras and candlesticks. Candle stands. Chandeliers. Wall brackets.
    - Lighting. French. Second Empire. (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Lighting. French. Art Nouveau. Art Deco. Box 37, Folder 6 (Box 37, Folder 6)
    - Lighting. German. (Box 37, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Candle stands. Candlesticks. Chandeliers. Lanterns. Indian.
    - Lighting. Italian (1 of 3). (Box 37, Folder 8)
    - Lighting. Italian (2 of 3). (Box 37, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Candle stands. Chandeliers. Contains correspondence from Neil H. Fox (1980).
    - Lighting. Italian (3 of 3). (Box 37, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Lanterns (19th century). Wall brackets.
    - Lighting. P - U. (Box 37, Folder 11)
    - Maps. (Box 37, Folder 12)
      Note: Maps also refers to globes and globe stands. Includes Dutch. English. French [Paris]. German. Italian. Scottish. Contains correspondence from Henry Sorensen (n.d.). Contains 2 photographs.
    - Marks. D - E. (Box 38, Folder 1)
      Note: Refers only to furniture marks. Includes Danish. Dutch. English.
    - Marks. French (1 of 5). (Box 38, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Inventory numbers. Château marks. Contains memorandum from Laury Libin, M.M.A. (1995). Contains 1 photograph and 1 rubbing.
    - Marks. French (2 of 5). (Box 38, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Cyphers. Estampilles (rubbings or photographs). Contains 15 rubbings.
    - Marks. French (3 of 5). (Box 38, Folder 4)
      Note: Includes Initials [A - L]. Contains correspondence to Steve Tipton (1978). Contains 1 photograph.
    - Marks. French (4 of 5). (Box 38, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Initials [M - Z].
    - Marks. French (5 of 5). (Box 38, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Labels and "etiquettes".
    - Marks. G - S. Various. (Box 38, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes German. Irish. Italian. Russian. Swedish. Non-furniture except gilt bronze. Contains 1 photograph.
    - Materials and techniques. A - D. (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - Materials and techniques. English (1 of 3). (Box 38, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Caning. Composition. Derbyshire spar. Dyeing on wood.
    - Materials and techniques. English (2 of 3). (Box 38, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Gilding. Graining. Japanning. Lacquer. Marble and stone.
    - Materials and techniques. English (3 of 3). (Box 38, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Marquetry and inlay. Metal. Pen work. Plastering. Plywood. Polish and veneer. Straw work. Wood.
    - Materials and techniques. French (1 of 3). (Box 38, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes Caning. Carving and painting. Chair making. Galuchat. Gilding. Japanning. Lacquer.
    - Materials and techniques. French (2 of 3). (Box 39, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Marble. Marbleizing. Marquetry. Metal. Painting. Plastering. Piqué and tortoiseshell. Veneer. Contains correspondence from Geneviève Bresc-Bautier, Musée du Louvre (1990).
    - Materials and techniques. French (3 of 3). (Box 39, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Vernis Martin. Woods. Contains correspondence from Peter F. Blume, Allentown Art Museum (1983).
    - Materials and techniques. German. (Box 39, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Amber. Coconut. Horn. Lacquer. Marble. Mother-of-pearl.
    - Materials and techniques. Irish. (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Materials and techniques. Italian (1 of 7). (Box 39, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Lacca povera. Lacquer. Lapis lazuli. Lava. Lumachella.
    - Materials and techniques. Italian (2 of 7). (Box 39, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Marble (painted, Agate Orientale, Alabaster, Aragonite, Carraro, Jasper, Onyx (Algerian), Paragone). Contains memorandum to Yale Kneeland, M.M.A. (1984) and Joseph J. Dodge, Cummer Gallery of Art (1970).See also: Series I. Research / Subseries I.B. General / f. Marble and mosaics.
    - Materials and techniques. Italian (3 of 7). (Box 39, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Mosaic (mosaicists, mixed, Cosmatesque work). Contains correspondence between Albert C. Goodyear and Preston Remington, M.M.A. (1931), from Galleria Sangiorgi di Giorgio Sangiorgi to John Goldsmith Phillips, M.M.A. (1958) and from Julius C. Walk and Son, Inc. to Preston Remington, M.M.A. (1931).
    - Materials and techniques. Italian (4 of 7). (Box 39, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Pietra dura (19th century, artisans, clocks). Contains 1 photograph and 1 slide.
    - Materials and techniques. Italian (5 of 7). (Box 39, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Porphyry.
    - Materials and techniques. Italian (6 of 7). (Box 39, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Scagliola (craftsmen). Stucco.
    - Materials and techniques. Italian (7 of 7). (Box 40, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Tortoiseshell and piqué. Wood (intarsia, marquetry, Certosina work).
    - Materials and techniques. Oriental (1 of 2). (Box 40, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Lacquer. Contains 1 photograph.
    - Materials and techniques. Oriental (2 of 2). (Box 40, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes Lacquer (Aventurine, lac-burgauté, coromadel, Portuguese).
    - Materials and techniques. Russian. (Box 40, Folder 4)
      Includes Lacquer. Malachite. Marble. Mosaic. Contains 1 slide.
    - Materials and techniques. S - W. (Box 40, Folder 5)
      Note: Includes Scottish. Spanish. U.S.A. (wood). Welsh.
    - Measurement. (Box 40, Folder 6)
    - Medals. (Box 40, Folder 7)
    - Microscopes and telescopes. (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - Museums and galleries. A - D. (Box 40, Folder 9)
      Note: Filed alphabetically by location. American museums by state or city and foreign institutions by country. Includes Australian. Austrian. Belgian. Brazilian. Canadian. Czechoslovakian. Danish. Dutch. Contains correspondence from Howard Creel Collinson, Royal Ontario Museum (1991) and to Kristian Jakobsen, Danish Museum of Decorative Art (1985).
    - Museums and galleries. English. (Box 40, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Finnish. Contains correspondence with Lucy Wood, Lady Lever Art Gallery (1983-1984).
    - Museums and galleries. French (1 of 2). (Box 40, Folder 11)
      Note: Includes Musée des Arts Décoratifs. Musée de Cluny. Musée du Louvre (Galerie d'Apollon).
    - Museums and galleries. French (2 of 2). (Box 40, Folder 12)
      Note: Includes A - Z. Contains correspondence from Jacqueline du Pasquier, Musée des Arts Décoratifs (1980), Francoise Reynaud, Musée Carnavalet (1979) and Jean-Daniel Ludmann, Musée des Arts Décoratifs (1988).
    - Museums and galleries. German. (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Museums and galleries. H - I. (Box 40, Folder 14)
      Note: Includes Hungarian. Irish. Israeli. Italian.
    - Museums and galleries. N - T. (Box 41, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Norwegian. Polish. Portuguese. Russian. Scottish. Spanish. Swedish. Swiss. Turkish. Contains correspondence to Robert E. Boyd, Jewelry and Gifts (1984).
    - Museums and galleries. U.S.A. (A - B). (Box 41, Folder 2)
      Note: Contains correspondence to Peter F. Blume, Allentown Art Museum (1984), from E. Bryding Adams, Birmingham Museum of Art (1983), from John David Farmer, Birmingham Museum of Art to Olga Raggio, M.M.A. (1977) and from William Rieder, M.M.A. to Jeffrey Munger, Museum of Fine Arts, Boston (1982).
    - Museums and galleries. U.S.A. (C - F). (Box 41, Folder 3)
      Note: Contains correspondence from Fleurette Kitchens, Cincinnati Art Museum (1981), Budd Harris Bishop, Columbus Museum of Art (1985), Vicki Vinson, Dallas Museum of Art (1988), Katherine S. Howe, Museum of Fine Arts, Houston (1987), Catherine Lippert, Indianapolis Museum of Art (1980) and Robert E. Fellows, University of Iowa (1982).
    - Museums and galleries. U.S.A. (K - T). (Box 41, Folder 4)
      Note: Contains correspondence from James R. Lamantia, New Orleans Museum of Art to James D. Draper, M.M.A. (1979), from Ghenete Zelleke, Carnegie Museum of Art (1988), Phillip M. Johnston, Museum of Art, Carnegie Institute (1984), Joseph R. Bliss, Virginia Museum of Fine Arts (1989), to Margaret Lichter, Saint Louis Art Museum (1993), to Kristan H. McKinsey, Saint Louis Art Museum (1988) and from Lynn E. Springer, Saint Louis Art Museum (1980).
    - Museums and galleries. U.S.A. (V - W). (Box 41, Folder 5)
      Note: Contains correspondence to David S. Brooke, Sterling and Francine Clark Art Institute (1984) and from Margaret S. Moore, Sterling and Francine Clark Art Institute (1989).
    - Musical instruments. (Box 41, Folder 6)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Belgian. Dutch. English. French. German. Italian. Portuguese. Russian. Scandinavian. Spanish.
    - Ornament prints. A - D. (Box 41, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Belgian. Czechoslovakian. Danish. Dutch. Cites - Daniel Marot. Contains correspondence from Linda Shulsky (1984).
    - Ornament prints. English (1 of 2). (Box 41, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Makers (A - L). Cites - William Kent, Matthias Lock.
    - Ornament prints. English (2 of 2). (Box 41, Folder 9)
      Note: Includes Makers (M - Z). Table settings. Cites - Augustus Welby Northmore Pugin, Charles Heathcote Tatham. Contains correspondence from Charles Truman, Asprey, London to William Reider, M.M.A. (1992).
    - Ornament prints. French. Makers (A). (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Ornament prints. French. Makers (B). (Box 42, Folder 2)
      Note: Cites - Jean Bérain, Jean-Jacques Boileau, Francois Boucher.
    - Ornament prints. French. Makers (C). (Box 42, Folder 3)
      Note: Cites - Gilles-Paul Cauvet, Charles-Louis Clérisseau.
    - Ornament prints. French. Makers (D). (Box 42, Folder 4)
      Note: Cites - Jean-Charles Delafosse, Jean-Démosthène Dugorc.
    - Ornament prints. French. Makers (F - H). (Box 42, Folder 5)
      Note: Cites - Desire Guilmard.
    - Ornament prints. French. Makers (L). (Box 42, Folder 6)
      Note: Cites - Richard de Lalonde, Charles Le Brun.
    - Ornament prints. French. Makers (M - O). (Box 42, Folder 7)
      Note: Cites - Juste Aurèle Meissonnier, Jean-Guillaume Moitte, Gilles-Marie Oppenord.
    - Ornament prints. French. Makers (P). (Box 42, Folder 8)
      Note: Cites - Charles Percier, Pierre-Josse Perrot, Ennemond-Alexandre Petitot, Alexis Peyrotte, Jean Pillement, Nicolas Pineau, Jean-Louis Prieur. Contains correspondence from Hans Ottomeyer, Müncher Stadtmuseum to Barbara Berliner, M.M.A. (1983).
    - Ornament prints. French. Makers (R - W). (Box 42, Folder 9)
      Note: Cites - Henri Salembier, Slodtz brothers (René Michel, Sebastien-Antoine).
    - Ornament prints. French. Mixed. (Box 42, Folder 10)
      Note: Includes Table settings.
    - Ornament prints. German. (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Ornament prints. Italian. (Box 43, Folder 1)
      Note: Includes Giocondo Albertolli. Giovanni-Battista Piranesi. Mixed. Table settings. Contains correspondence from V. Bielitzky, Kunsthandel D. Mendelsohn, Hamburg (1990).
    - Ornament prints. R - S. (Box 43, Folder 2)
      Note: Includes Russian. Scandinavian. Scottish. Swiss.
    - Ornament prints. [Types]. Chinoiseries. (Box 43, Folder 3)
      Note: Includes English. French. German. Italian.
    - Ornament prints. [Types]. Japonaiserie. (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Ornament prints. [Types]. Singeries. (Box 43, Folder 5)
      Note: Contains correspondence to Mrs. Marshall Roscoe, North Deighton Manor (1979).
    - Ornament prints. [Types]. Turqueries. (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Ovens and stoves. (Box 43, Folder 7)
      Note: Includes Austrian. English. French. German. Italian. Russian. Scandinavian. Swiss. Contains 1 slide.
    - Painting. A - D. (Box 43, Folder 8)
      Note: Includes Austrian. Belgian. Danish. Dutch. Cites - Maulbertsch, D'Egmont, Van Dael, Van Der Meulen, Teniers, Ringelhan, Juel, Van Blarenberge, Grevenbroeck, Troost, de Lairesse, Van Spaendeonck, Saenredam, de Wit. Contains correspondence from Viggo Bech Rambusch, Rambusch Decorating Company (1969).
    - Painting. English. [Includes 19th century.] (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Painting. English. Makers (A - H). (Box 43, Folder 10)
      Note: Cites - Abbott, Alma-Tadema, Anderson, Barlow, Beaulerk, Bermingham, Birket-Foster, Bonington, Boulton, Boys, Brookshaw, Cipriani, Cosway, Cotes, Danby, Dance, Delacour, Devis, Dixon, Dobson, Gainsborough, Gardner, Gibbons, Gavin Hamilton, Hugh Douglas Hamilton, Harrison, Hayman, Healy, Highmore, Hill, Hoare, Hudson.
    - Painting. English. Makers (J - S). (Box 43, Folder 11)
      Note: Cites - Judson, Kauffmann, Kent, Lambert, Lanoon, Lasson, Laszlo, Lavery, Lawrence, Lear, Leighton, Le Marchand, Mercier, Methuer, Millais, Monamey, Morland, Mortimer, Munnings, Opie, Patch, Pergolesi, Pope, Ramsay, Rebecca, Reiwagle, Reynolds, Richmond, Rowlandson, Sandby, Sandys, Stone.
    - Painting. English. Makers (T - Z). (Box 43, Folder 12)
      Note: Cites - Thornhill, Turner, Walpole, Wheatley, Wilkie, Wimsatt, Wooton, Wright, Zoffany, Zucchi.
    - Painting. French. (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Painting. French. Makers (A - B). (Box 44, Folder 2)
      Note: Cites - d'Arles, Aubry, Aved, Auvray, Bachelier, Bailly, Balze, Beaubrun, Baugin, Bellangé, Belle, Beraud, Bernard, Beroud, Berthelemy, Bertin, Berty, Beshard, Biard, Bisard, Blanchet, Boileau, Boilly, Boitard, Bosio, Boucher, Boulanger, Boullogne, Boulogne, Bourdon, Bouys, Boze, Bredin, Brenet, Broussard, Brunel.
    - Painting. French. Makers (C). (Box 44, Folder 3)
      Note: Cites - Callet, Carme, Carmontelle, Carrey, Casanova, Philippe de Champaigne, Jean-Baptiste de Champaigne, Chaplin, Charpentier, Chéron, Ciceri, Claude, Clerisseau, Clermont, Clouet, Cochin, Gille Colson, Conte, Coqueret, Cotelle, Coupin de la Couperie, Courtois, Antoine Coypel, Charles Coypel, Noel Coypel.
    - Painting. French. Makers (D). (Box 44, Folder 4)